You saw how violin plots can be used to depict
你已经知道了如何使用小提琴图来描绘
the relationship between a quantitative variable and a qualitative variable.
数值变量和分类变量之间的关系
An alternative plot that you might want to use, is the box plot.
然而你还有另一种选择 那就是箱线图
In a box plot, we compute descriptive statistics within
在箱线图中 我们计算每一级的描述性统计数据
each level and depict them graphically using a box and whiskers.
绘制矩形箱和须线来表示这些数据
The central line and each box indicates the median of
每个箱子的中心线表示数据的中位数
the data and the upper and lower edges show the first and third quartiles.
而上下边缘则表示第一四分位数和第三四分位数
Whiskers are extended from the top and bottom of
从箱子顶端和底部延伸出来的须线
the boxes to indicate the largest and smallest values.
代表最大值和最小值
25 percent of the data falls between each set of horizontal lines.
有百分之 25 的数据位于每组水平线段之间
Box plots often have outliers plotted as points beyond the ends of the whiskers.
在箱线图中 超出须线范围的点表示异常值
The most common upper bound on the length of the whiskers is
须线长度上限通常是
1.5 times the interquartile range or box length.
四分位差或箱子高度的 1.5 倍
For the scores posted by North,
在北队发布的得分中
the IQR is 5.5 and the maximum whisker length is 8.25.
四分位差为 5.5 须线的最大长度为 8.25
If we have outliers that are further than this distance
如果我们有异常值
above the top of the box are below the bottom of the box,
超过箱子上方 8.25 或是超过箱子下方 8.25
they are depicted as single points and the whiskers are only extended
它们将在图中被描绘为单独的点 须线到最远点
to the farthest point within the 1.5 times IQR range.
之间的距离不会超过四分位差的 1.5 倍
In this case, the maximum bound for the upper whisker is 66.75,
在这个例子中 上方须线的上限值为 66.75
so the maximum value of 68 is depicted as
因此这组数据的最大值 68 便是一个异常值
an outlier and the whisker is placed at the next largest value of 63.
须线的顶端横线处于数据中第二大的值 63 的位置
While box plots do a fine job of summarizing the data,
尽管箱线图能够很好地概括数据
there are some distributional details that can get lost.
但我们往往会丢失一些数据分布的细节
For example, the box plot reveals more clearly than
比如 与小提琴图相比
the violin plot that the North team had
箱线图能够更直观地表明北队的表现最差
the worst performance and the Central team the best.
而中队的表现最好
However, it is not obvious from the box plot that
然而南队的得分
the South team scores include a broad plateaus between about 60 and 62 points,
大多处于 60 分和 62 分的区间内 这在箱线图中并不明显
as you can see in the violin plot.
但在小提琴图中 你可以清晰地看到这一点
One alternative approach for showing summary statistics is to start with
另一种展示概括统计量的好方法 是使用小提琴图
a violin plot and then add lines to the curves to denote quartile points.
并在曲线中添加线段来表示四分位点
However, this is a bit less direct than the box plot.
然而 这比绘制箱线图要麻烦一点
So, when it comes to explanatory data visualization,
因此 当我们进行解释性可视化时
you might want to choose a box plot for simplicity and focus.
你也许会选择箱线图 因为它更简单和直观